Register to the Joseph Abraham Mendenhall papers, 1927-2011
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Abraham Mendenhall papers
1927-2011
2011C52
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes (7.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, printed matter, personal documents, and photographs relating to American foreign relations and to the Vietnam War.
Mendenhall, Joseph Abraham, 1920-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1920 Born, Calvert, Maryland
1940 B.A., University of Delaware
1941-1946 U.S. Army service, attained rank of captain
1946-1975 U.S. Foreign Service officer
1946-1949 Vice Consul, Istanbul, Turkey
1949-1951 Assistant Chief, Economic Cooperation Administration Mission to Iceland
1952-1955 Second Secretary of Embassy, Switzerland
1955-1959 Department of State Bureau of Southeast Asian Affairs officer, Washington, D.C.
1959-1962 Counselor of Embassy, South Vietnam
1962-1963 U.S. National War College student
1963-1964 Director, Department of State Vietnam Working Group, Washington, D.C.
1964-1965 Director, Department of State Office of Far Eastern Regional Affairs, Washington, D.C.
1965-1968 Director, U.S. Agency for International Development Mission to Laos
1968-1970 Deputy and acting Assistant Administrator for Vietnam, U.S. Agency for International Development, Washington, D.C.
1970-1972 U.S. Foreign Service inspector
1972-1975 Ambassador to Madagascar
1975 Retired and took up residence in Italy
1992 Returned to the United States
Scope and Content of Collection
Joseph A. Mendenhall's career as a U.S. Foreign Service officer was highlighted by specialization in Southeast Asian affairs during the Vietnam War era. Both on the ground in Vietnam (1959-1962) and Laos (1965-1968) and in senior Department of State positions in Washington, D.C., including that of Director of the Department's Office of Far Eastern Regional Affairs, he was intimately involved in the formulation and execution of American foreign policy in the area. The U.S. Foreign Service File in his papers presents only a partial record of his government service, as most of the official documents that passed through his hands remain in possession of the United States government. However, the file does include the texts and outline notes of many speeches at public functions and of presentations at many internal staff meetings and in-house Department of State conferences and briefing sessions. These afford an inside view of foreign policy formation.
After his retirement in 1975, Mendenhall devoted much thought to retrospective analysis of the Vietnam War, a war that he continued to believe could and should have been won. He also maintained a lively interest in new issues in American foreign policy. His views on these matters are expressed in letters in the Retirement Formal Correspondence file and in writings, published and unpublished, in the Retirement Speeches and Writings file.
A Personal Correspondence file accounts for a large portion of the collection. This consists of informal correspondence with family and friends over the whole of Mendenhall's life, and also includes the correspondence of his wife Leone. Many letters are from the Mendenhalls to their respective parents. This series is noteworthy for its unusually complete and detailed description of the life of a Foreign Service family frequently stationed abroad. It also reflects subjective reactions to local and world events. Chronological arrangement facilitates correlation with Mendenhall's various career postings.
Ambassador Mendenhall donated his papers to the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
United States.--Agency for International Development.; United States.--Dept. of State.; Diplomats--United States.; Laos--Foreign relations--United States.; Madagascar--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Laos.; United States--Foreign relations--Madagascar.; United States--Foreign relations--Vietnam.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam--Foreign relations--United States.
- Early Life and Ancestry, 1927-2010 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Genealogical, school, and military service records.
  - Genealogy
    - General, 1994-2008 (Folder 1: 1)
      Mendenhall family history, with related charts, correspondence, and miscellany.
    - Mendenhall Family Association newsletters, 1996-2010 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Education
    - Elementary and high school report cards and memorabilia, 1927-1936 (Folder 1: 3)
    - University of Delaware, 1937-1940 (Folder 1: 4)
      Correspondence, campus newspaper issues, and university history.
    - Law school and graduate school application correspondence, 1940-1946 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Military service, 1941-1955 (Folder 1: 6)
    U.S. Army personnel file, War Department application correspondence, and Air Force Reserve discharge certificate.
- U.S. Foreign Service File, 1945-1976 (Box 1-5)
  Personnel file, official correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, and printed matter.
  - Department of State personnel file, 1945-1975 (Folder 1: 7)
    Includes application materials and evaluation reports.
  - Official correspondence
    - 1945-1958 (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1959-1962 (Folder 1: 9)
      Includes correspondence with Elbridge Durbrow.
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 1: 10)
      Includes U.S. National War College correspondence.
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 2: 1)
      Includes correspondence with Chester Bowles and William H. Sullivan and with Edward M. Kennedy and other members of Congress.
    - 1969-1971 (Folder 2: 2)
      Includes correspondence with Edgar Buell, Ellsworth Bunker, William H. Sullivan, and members of Congress.
    - 1972 (Folder 2: 3)
      Mainly letters of congratulation upon ambassadorial appointment. Includes correspondence with Ellsworth Bunker, Shelby Cullom Davis and William Rogers, and with J. Caleb Boggs and other members of Congress.
    - 1973-1974 (Folder 2: 4)
      Includes correspondence with William H. Sullivan.
    - 1975 (Folder 2: 5)
      Includes correspondence with Henry A. Kissinger and Eliot Richardson.
  - Speeches and writings
    - Orientation talk on political background of Vietnam for newly arrived Americans in Vietnam, mimeograph, 1962 March 30 (Folder 2: 6)
    - "Viet-Nam: Land of Crisis," University News (University of Delaware publication), 1962 Summer (Folder 2: 7)
      Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence.
    - Department of State seminar on collective security in the Far East, presentation outline, 1965 February 2 (Folder 2: 8)
    - Department of State briefing on foreign policy in the Far East, presentation outline, 1965 April 16 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Counterintelligence seminar on Southeast Asia, presentation outline, 1965 April 21 (Folder 2: 10)
    - Debate on Vietnam, Freedom Forum, Albion College, Albion, Michigan, 1965 May 13 (Folder 2: 11)
      Presentation outline, correspondence, and press coverage.
    - Talk to Military Government Association on Vietnam, Portland, Oregon, presentation outline, 1965 May 29 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Lecture on Communist challenge in Asia, Westminister College, Fulton, Missouri, presentation outline, 1965 July 12 (Folder 2: 13)
    - Counterintelligence seminar on Vietnam, presentation outline, 1965 August 13 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Statement to press upon appointment as U.S. Agency for International Development director in Laos, typescript, 1965 September 8 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Talk to AID Laos Mission staff, presentation outline, 1965 September 24 (Folder 2: 16)
    - Briefing on AID program for Senator Edward M. Kennedy, presentation outline, 1965 October 27 (Folder 2: 17)
    - Talk on rural development program, presentation outline, 1965 October 31 (Folder 2: 18)
    - General orientation talk on AID program, presentation outline and background data, 1966 January 18 (Folder 2: 19)
    - Remarks at laying of cornerstone for medical warehouse, Vientiane, Laos, typescript, 1966 May 12 (Folder 2: 20)
    - Talk to Laotian teachers participating in training program in Thailand, typescript and Lao translation, 1966 June 7 (Folder 2: 21)
    - Talk to Rotary Club (Vientiane?) on U.S. aid to Laos, typescript and French translation, 1966 July 11 (Folder 2: 22)
    - Talk at far cargo vessel ceremony, Laos, typescript, 1966 July 12 (Folder 2: 23)
    - Talk to AID cluster managers, Laos, presentation outline, 1966 July 27 (Folder 2: 24)
    - Talk at presentation of certificates to Laotian teachers, typescript, 1966 August 18 (Folder 2: 25)
    - Talk and briefing to Laotian trainees, typescript and presentation outline, 1966 September 22-23 (Folder 2: 26)
    - Talk at Vientiane Prefecture ceremony, typescript, 1966 October 11 (Folder 2: 27)
    - Voice of America interview on AID program in Laos, transcript, 1966 November 22 (Folder 2: 28)
    - Speech to Laotian trainees, typescript, 1966 December 7 (Folder 2: 29)
    - Remarks at dedication of medical warehouse, That Luang, Laos, typescript and French translation, 1966 December 8 (Folder 2: 30)
    - Briefing on AID program for Senator Stuart Symington, presentation outline and background data, 1966 December 20 (Folder 2: 31)
    - Remarks at Ministry of Finance ceremony, Vientiane, Laos, typescript (in French) and background data, 1967 January 17 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Refugee relief officers conference, presentation outline, 1967 January 18 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Speech at dedication of Sedone Valley development projects, Laos, mimeograph and French translation, 1967 January 27 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Talk to U.S. Information Service personnel, Laos, presentation outline, 1967 February 7 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Speech at agricultural conference, Vientiane, Laos, mimeograph, 1967 March 7 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Speech at signing of small industries project agreement, Vientiane, Laos, typescript and French translation, 1967 March 10 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Speech at orthopedic center, Vientiane, Laos, mimeograph and French translation, 1967 March 17 (Folder 3: 7)
    - Remarks at school dedication, Kengkok, Laos, mimeograph, 1967 April 10 (Folder 3: 8)
    - Staff meeting, presentation outline, 1967 April 27 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Remarks at groupes scolaires dedication, Pakse, Laos, mimeograph and French translation, 1967 May 18 (Folder 3: 10)
    - Remarks at groupes scolaires dedications, Xieng Ngeun and Luang Prabang, Laos, 1967 May 19 (Folder 3: 11)
      Typescript, mimeograph, and French and Lao translations.
    - Speech at groupes scolaires dedication, Vientiane, Laos, mimeograph and French and Lao translations, 1967 May 22 (Folder 3: 12)
    - Talk to Chao Muong personnel, presentation outline, 1967 May 29 (Folder 3: 13)
    - Speech at dedication of Hia Nakok Dam, Laos, mimeograph and French and Lao translations, 1967 June 29 (Folder 3: 14)
    - Speech to graduating nurses, Vientiane, Laos, mimeograph, 1967 July 15 (Folder 3: 15)
    - Speech at dedication of Hong Sa-Tha Souang Road, Laos, typescript, 1967 December 3 (Folder 3: 16)
    - "The United States National Interest in Viet-Nam,", 1967 December 20 (Folder 3: 17)
      Typescript statement prepared for Senator Abraham Ribicoff and correspondence with Ribicoff.
    - Talk on AID program in Laos, presentation outline, 1968 January 25 (Folder 3: 18)
    - Conference on changing the people of Laos, presentation outline, 1968 February 10 (Folder 3: 19)
    - Conference on community development in Laos, presentation outline and agenda, 1968 February 15 (Folder 3: 20)
    - Remarks at dedication of groupe scolaire and warehouse, Sayaboury, Laos, typescript, 1968 May 14 (Folder 3: 21)
    - Remarks at dedication of groupe scolaire and warehouse, Ban Houei Sai, Laos, typescript, 1968 May 15 (Folder 3: 22)
    - "Is Laos a Viable State?," typescript, 1968 September 10 (Folder 3: 23)
    - "The Aims and Methods of U.S. Aid Programs in Southeast Asia," speech, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois, typescript, 1968 November 14 (Folder 3: 24)
    - Notes on book by David Schoenbrun, Vietnam: How We Got In, How to Get Out, 1968 November 30 (Folder 3: 25)
    - "TV Notes" (reference unclear; re Vietnam), 1968 December 10 (Folder 3: 26)
    - "Progress in Vietnam's 'Other War,'" typescript, 1968 December (Folder 3: 27)
    - Talk on Vietnam economic-civil front, presentation outline, 1969 January 24 (Folder 3: 28)
    - "Miracle Rice in Vietnam," letter to the editor, Baltimore Sun, printed copy, 1969 February 14 (Folder 3: 29)
    - Statement to U.S. House Foreign Affairs Committee on Vietnam AID program for FY 1970, typescript, 1969 June 16 (Folder 3: 30)
    - Statement to U.S. House Appropriations Committee Foreign Operations Subcommittee on Vietnam AID program for FY 1970, typescript, 1969 July 14 (Folder 3: 31)
    - Talk on Vietnam to President's Science Advisory Council, presentation outline, 1969 November 22 (Folder 3: 32)
    - Statement to U.S. Senate Appropriations Committee Foreign Operations Subcommittee on Vietnam AID program for FY 1970, typescript, 1969 November 26 (Folder 3: 33)
    - Talk on Vietnam (occasion unclear), presentation outline, 1969 December (Folder 3: 34)
  - Assignment to Turkey, 1948-1952 (Folder 3: 35)
    Memorandum and speech by Esther W. Boyer on 500th anniversary of conquest of Constantinople.
  - Assignment to Iceland, 1951-1953 (Folder 3: 36)
    Background data, and printed article on Marshall Plan (in Icelandic).
  - Assignment to Switzerland, 1954-1955 (Folder 3: 37)
    Diplomatic corps directory, printed article, and ocean liner passenger list.
  - Assignments re Vietnam
    - South Vietnamese government directories
      - 1960 (Folder 3: 38)
      - 1961 (Folder 4: 1)
      - 1962 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Diplomatic corps directory and U.S. Embassy personnel directory, 1960 and 1962 (Folder 4: 3)
    - U.S. Operations Mission to Vietnam annual reports, 1958 and 1960 (Folder 4: 4)
    - U.S. Agency for International Development Mission to Vietnam annual reports, 1968 and 1969 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Expense vouchers, 1959-1962 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Miscellany, 1951-1968 (Folder 4: 7)
      Memoranda, speeches by others, and lists.
    - Printed matter, 1963-1975 (Folder 4: 8)
      Background printed articles and serial issues.
  - Assignment to U.S. National War College, 1962-1963 (Folder 4: 9)
    Faculty and student rosters and annual report.
  - Assignments re Laos
    - Schedules and guest lists, 1965-1968 (Folder 4: 10)
    - Background and briefing materials on Laos and on U.S. aid to Laos, 1959-1968 (Folder 5: 1)
    - Miscellany, 1961-1974 (Folder 5: 2)
      Speeches by others, printed articles, and memorabilia.
  - Assignment to Madagascar, 1972-1975 (Folder 5: 3)
    Memoranda, list of Madagascar government officials, Madagascar newspaper issues, and memorabilia.
  - Miscellany, 1946-1975 (Folder 5: 4)
    Schedules, lists, biographical data, Department of State publications, Nigerian and South Korean newspaper issues, and memorabilia.
  - Press coverage
    Official publications and news stories re Mendenhall's diplomatic career.
    - 1960-1969 (Folder 5: 5)
    - 1972 (ambassadorial appointment) (Folder 5: 6)
    - 1975-1976 (retirement) (Folder 5: 7)
- Personal Correspondence, 1938-2011 (Box 6-14)
  Informal correspondence with family and friends, arranged chronologically. Includes correspondence of Leone Mendenhall, wife of Joseph Mendenhall.
  - 1938-1940 (Folder 6: 1)
  - 1941 (Folder 6: 2)
  - 1942 (Folder 6: 3)
  - 1943 (Folder 6: 4)
  - 1944 (Folder 7: 1)
  - 1945 (Folder 7: 2-3)
  - 1946 (Folder 7: 4-7)
  - 1947 (Folder 8: 1-2)
  - 1948 (Folder 8: 3-4)
  - 1949 (Folder 8: 5-8)
  - 1950 (Folder 8: 9-11)
  - 1951 (Folder 9: 1)
  - 1952 (Folder 9: 2)
  - 1953 (Folder 9: 3)
  - 1954 (Folder 9: 4)
  - 1955 (Folder 9: 5)
  - 1956 (Folder 9: 6)
  - 1957 (Folder 9: 7)
  - 1958 (Folder 9: 8)
  - 1959 (Folder 9: 9-10)
  - 1960 (Folder 9: 1-12)
  - 1961 (Folder 10: 1-2)
  - 1962 (Folder 10: 3-4)
  - 1963 (Folder 10: 5)
  - 1964 (Folder 10: 6)
  - 1965 (Folder 10: 7-8)
  - 1966 (Folder 10: 9-10)
  - 1967 (Folder 11: 1-2)
  - 1968 (Folder 11: 3-4)
  - 1969 (Folder 11: 5)
  - 1970 (Folder 11: 6)
  - 1971 (Folder 12: 1)
  - 1972 (Folder 12: 2)
  - 1973 (Folder 12: 3)
  - 1974 (Folder 12: 4)
  - 1975 (Folder 12: 5)
  - 1976 (Folder 13: 1)
  - 1977 (Folder 13: 2)
  - 1978 (Folder 13: 3)
  - 1979 (Folder 13: 4)
  - 1980 (Folder 13: 5)
  - 1981 (Folder 13: 6)
  - 1982 (Folder 13: 7)
  - 1983-1984 (Folder 13: 8)
  - 1985-1986 (Folder 13: 9)
  - 1987-1989 (Folder 14: 1)
  - 1990-1993 (Folder 14: 2)
  - 1994-1996 (Folder 14: 3)
  - 1997-1999 (Folder 14: 4)
  - 2000-2002 (Folder 14: 5)
  - 2003-2005 (Folder 14: 6)
  - 2006-2008 (Folder 14: 7)
  - 2009-2011 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Undated (Folder 14: 9)
- Retirement Formal Correspondence, 1975-2010 (Box 14-15)
  Correspondence on political, foreign policy, and other subjects, arranged chronologically. Letters to members of Congress expressing Mendenhall's views and correspondence with University of Delaware officials re alumni affairs occur throughout.
  - 1975-1979 (Folder 14: 10)
  - 1980-1982 (Folder 14: 11)
    Includes correspondence with Fernando E. Rondon and William H. Sullivan, and with U.S. News and World Report Books re projected book on Vietnam War.
  - 1983-1985 (Folder 14: 12)
    Includes correspondence with Fernando E. Rondon and William H. Sullivan.
  - 1986-1989 (Folder 15: 1)
    Includes correspondence with Bui Diem, and with Brian VanDeMark re his dissertation on Vietnam War policy.
  - 1990-1993 (Folder 15: 2)
  - 1994-1996 (Folder 15: 3)
    Includes correspondence with Marshall Green and letters to William E. Colby and Henry A. Kissinger.
  - 1997-1999 (Folder 15: 4)
  - 2000-2002 (Folder 15: 5)
    Includes correspondence with Elbridge Colby.
  - 2003-2006 (Folder 15: 6)
    Includes letter to Paul Wolfowitz.
  - 2007-2010 (Folder 15: 7)
- Retirement Speeches and Writings, 1976-2011 (Box 15-18)
  Holographs, typescripts, printed copies, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically.
  - "Missing Madonna of Carda Mourned by Italian Villagers," typescript and correspondence, 1976 (Folder 15: 8)
  - "Communist Vietnam and the Border War: Victim or Aggressor?," Strategic Review, 1978 Summer (Folder 15: 9)
  - "Essentials for Economic Development," typescript and correspondence, 1978 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Review of William Colby and Peter Forbath, Honorable Men: My Life in the CIA, Strategic Review, 1979 Spring (Folder 15: 11)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence. Includes correspondence with Colby.
  - "Could the Vietnam War Have Been Won?," typescript and correspondence, 1979 (Folder 15: 12)
  - "Next Vietnamese Communist Target: Northeast Thailand?," typescript and letter, 1979 (Folder 15: 13)
  - "Laos: Vietnam's Stepping-Stone to Thailand," Conflict, 1980 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Review of Amphay Doré, Le partage du Mékong, typescript, circa 1980 (Folder 16: 2)
  - "Southeast Asia: Challenge and Opportunity for the Reagan Administration," typescript and correspondence, 1980 (Folder 16: 3)
  - Review of Ronald Steel, Walter Lippmann and the American Century, Strategic Review, 1981 Spring (Folder 16: 4)
  - "The Portents of the New Neutralism and Neo-Isolationism," typescript and correspondence, 1982 (Folder 16: 5)
  - Review of Norman Podhoretz, Why We Were in Vietnam, Strategic Review, 1983 Spring (Folder 16: 6)
  - Interview with U.S. Department of State Office of the Historian re involvement with Vietnam War policy, 1983 December 27 (Folder 16: 7)
    Memorandum of interview prepared by the Office of the Historian, photocopies of supporting documentation, and correspondence.
  - "The Meaning of Vietnam for El Salvador," typescript and correspondence, 1983 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Review of Zbigniew Brzezinski, Power and Principle: Memoirs of the National Security Adviser, 1977-1981, Strategic Review, 1984 Spring (Folder 16: 9)
  - Review of Gary Sick, All Fall Down: America's Tragic Encounter with Iran, holograph, 1986 (Folder 16: 10)
  - Review of Neil Sheehan, A Bright Shining Lie: John Paul Vann and America in Vietnam, holograph and correspondence, 1988 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Review of William E. Colby with James McCargar, Lost Victory: A Firsthand Account of America's Sixteen-Year Involvement in Vietnam, Strategic Review, 1990 Winter (Folder 16: 12)
    Typescript, printed copy, and letter.
  - "America in Crisis," typescript and correspondence, 1990 (Folder 16: 13)
  - "The United States and China: A 21st Century Superpower Confrontation?," typescript and correspondence, 1993 (Folder 16: 14)
  - "No to U.S. Troops in Bosnia," typescript and letter, 1995 (Folder 16: 15)
  - "America at the Threshold of the 21st Century," holograph, 1997 (Folder 17: 1)
  - "What Is a Viable U.S. Politico-Military Strategy vis-à-vis China?," typescript, 1998 (Folder 17: 2)
  - "Syria: Little-Known Treasure Trove for Tourists," typescript, 1990s (Folder 17: 3)
  - "America's Geopolitical Context: Past and Future, or the Geopolitical Destiny of the United States," holograph, 2000 (Folder 17: 4)
  - "A Long-Enduring Friendship with Marge," (re Marjorie Tilghman), typescript and correspondence, 2000 (Folder 17: 5)
  - "Beware of the Big Lie," typescript and letter, 2001 (Folder 17: 6)
  - "The Struggle with Militant Islam," typescript and correspondence, 2001 (Folder 17: 7)
  - "The United States and Europe," typescript and correspondence, 2002 (Folder 17: 8)
  - "The Foreign Policy Scorecard of America's Presidents since World War II," holograph, 2003 (Folder 17: 9)
  - "The Korean Conundrum," typescript and correspondence, 2003 (Folder 17: 10)
  - "Assessment of U.S. Iraq Policy," typescript and letter, 2004 (Folder 17: 11)
  - Message to funeral of Icelandic diplomat Thorhallur Argivisson, holograph and letter, 2005 November 18 (Folder 17: 12)
  - "Can America Long Endure?," typescript and letter, 2005 (Folder 17: 13)
  - "Lessons from the Vietnam War for Iraq," typescript and correspondence, 2005 (Folder 17: 14)
  - "The Past Can Help Counterinsurgency in Iraq," typescript and correspondence, 2006 (Folder 17: 15)
  - "America's Loss of Memory in Both the Vietnam and Iraq Wars," typescript and letter, 2008 (Folder 17: 16)
  - "Why the Japan-India Security Pact Is of Prime Importance to the U.S.," typescript and letter, 2008 (Folder 17: 17)
  - Letters to the editor, typescripts and some printed copies, 1979-2011 (Folder 17: 18)
  - Miscellaneous draft holographs (Folder 17: 19)
- Biographical and Personal File, 1942-1989 (Box 18)
  Biographical, family, and personal miscellanea.
  - Personal and financial records, 1942-1989 (Folder 18: 1)
    Includes Who's Who biographical entries and University of Delaware Alumni Wall of Fame citation.
  - Family miscellanea, mainly re children, 1951-1979 (Folder 18: 2)
  - Miscellany (Folder 18: 3)
    Includes appointment book and notebook.
- Subject File, 1954-2009 (Box 18)
  Printed matter and notes, arranged by subject.
  - Iraq, 2003-2008 (Folder 18: 4)
    Printed articles and writings by others.
  - Vietnam and Laos
    - General, 1980-2008 (Folder 18: 5)